NO BOY NO CRY ore zenshin GO
no boy, no cry, I advance go!
shounen yo kiite kure
hey boys, listen up
ningen nante taishita mon ja nai sa
humans aren't such a big deal
ashita nante moui ranai kara
who needs tomorrow anyway
nigitta kobushi wo kakusu na yo
so don't hide your fists
fuan ni yume wo
you're not old enough
uri tobasu hodo mada oiborechainai daro
to sell your dreams away to uncertainty
shounen yo kokoro no jyuu no
hey boys, you're the only ones
hikigane wo hikeru no wa kimi dake sa
who can pull the trigger in your heart
subete no wakamono wa iitta
all the kids said
doushi yo mo naku kudaranai
we're living in this senseless, ridiculous,
kono subarashii sekai ni tattaima ikiteiru kara
awesome world right at this moment,
subete no wakamono wa iitta
all the kids said
subete no hontou to uso wo
don't forget every truth or lie
kesshite wasurete shima wa nai you ni
subete no wakamono wa iitta
all the kids said
shinu ni wa mosugiru darou
we're way too young to die
shiraketa tsura ga naranderu karappo no kono machi de
in this empty town lined with empty faces
subete no wakamono wa iitta
all the kids took off
kaze no nai kono yoru ni
into this windless night
nanika wo kaeyou to shiteru kara
because they want to change something
With this you've woken up, right?
We had a hindrance back then...
but it won't be like
that this time.
I'll show you...
the true power of Sharingan.
Fine... Then I'll go all out too!
You take a good look
with your Sharingan...
at my Ninja Way!
Shadow Clone Jutsu!
You can't beat me by just pointlessly...
increasing the number!
You little...!
I can spot the real body in
one shot with my Sharingan.
I deliberately went along
with your game...
I won't go easy on you now!
Fire Style: Fire Ball Jutsu!
{Father and Son
{The Cracked Family Crest
What was up...
with those eyes of nii-san's?
That wasn't...
just an ordinary Sharingan.
And... quite a bit of time's
passed since then...
but things are still kind of awkward
between him and Father.
Good morning, Father...
Yeah, good morning.
Sasuke... how have things
been going at the Academy lately?
It's boring with just school classes.
I'm always number one so...
Fire Style: Fire Ball Jutsu!
W-Wow...
This is the fundamental
Jutsu of the Uchiha.
The Sign is as I taught you earlier.
You build up Chakra
stop it once at around between
the mouth and the chest area
and spew it out at once after that.
— Try it.
— Okay!
Father... is teaching me Jutsu himself.
Finally... Father has also recognized me!
I must live up to his expectations!
I too can...!
Fire Style: Fire Ball Jutsu!
Sure enough it won't go like
it did with Itachi, huh?
It might've still been
too soon for you.
A member of the Uchiha Clan
is not recognized as full-fledged
until they can use the Fire Style.
The Uchiha crest...
means those who possess
the Uchiha that controls fire.
Fire Style: Fire Ball Jutsu!
Damn it! One more time!
Today for sure!
Fire Style: Fire Ball Jutsu!
Sasuke...!
Wait a minute.
What is it?
What...?
Oh... Don't move.
Okay, finished!
Mother...
Hmm?
No... It's nothing.
Okay...
Fire Style: Fire Ball Jutsu!
Sure enough it won't go
like it did with Itachi, huh?
It might've still been
too soon for you...
I'm just getting started.
Damn it! One more time!
Fire Style: Fire Ball Jutsu!
Father!
Hmm?
One more time...
Please join me.
It's still too soon for you.
Even if I were to teach you
for only after a week...
It's not that...
I've gotten... the hang of the Jutsu.
So I want you to see it.
Failure is not an option!
Fire Style: Fire Ball Jutsu!
That's my boy.
You've done well.
From now on, improve yourself
and soar large
so as not to bring shame
to the crest on your back.
Right!
And... let me say one thing.
Don't chase after
your older brother anymore.
Mother...?
Hmm?
What does Father really think of
nii-san and me?
What is it all of a sudden?
The other day Father said to me
"That's my boy".
He'd always said that only to nii-san.
So I was really happy.
I see... Good for you.
But lately Father and nii-san
haven't been getting along so...
I was thinking...
that I might just be
a replacement for nii-san.
Your older brother's your older brother.
And you are you.
Your father cares deeply
about you both.
Then why does he only think
about nii-san?!
That's not it...
Your father has to protect
the Uchiha Clan
as a representative of the clan.
What about it?!
Itachi is just bigger than you
and is your elder.
He'll naturally be entrusted
with that much more work
for the clan, right?
Your father is the supervisor
of the work so...
it might be that his eyes were
likely to go towards your older brother.
But this is just between us.
When he's with me,
your father does nothing
but talk about you.
He's just always sullen
and awkward so...
I'll catch up to nii-san no matter what!
Damn it...!
Nii-san's back is still
far out of reach.
Forgive me Sasuke...
Maybe another time.
Clan... Clan...
You measure incorrectly
the size of your own "vessels"
and don't know the depth of mine
so you grovel there.
My "vessel" is
dismayed at this foolish clan.
I feel like... ever since that day
he hasn't been the same
as he was before.
Nii-san...
Today when school's finished
will you join me for
some Shuriken Jutsu training?
I'm busy.
You should have Father teach you.
But even I know that you're better
at Shuriken Jutsu than Father is.
You always treat me like
a nuisance like that.
Forgive me Sasuke.
Maybe next time...
I don't have the time to
be dealing with you today.
You always say "Forgive me Sasuke"
and poke me on the forehead.
and you say "today"
but it never happens.
Thank goodness...
he's the same as before.
Nii-san...
His eyes looking back
at Father that time...
It wasn't just an ordinary Sharingan...
And...
Father...?
Hmm?
Are there several types
of Sharingan?
Oh... You're already interested
in Sharingan?
However, it's still too soon for you.
It's totally different from
the Fire Style Jutsu.
But someday I too...!
After all... I'm your kid so.
Indeed there is a Visual Jutsu
above the Sharingan
the Mangekyo Sharingan.
Mangekyo Sharingan...
In the long history of the Uchiha
it's a legendary Visual Jutsu
that only a few develop.
And it's said that it only opened
under a particular condition.
A particular condition...?
Don't chase after your
older brother anymore.
I wonder what he thinks of my
relationship with nii-san?
Father...
Why doesn't nii-san care about me?
He's a bit peculiar...
He's a type of person who doesn't
care for making friends with people.
Why?
Who knows...?
Even I, his father, can't read that boy.
Here I spoke because I wanted
more of nii-san's attention.
Father isn't against it.
Here Sasuke!
Your box lunch.
I'll watch your Shuriken practice
after you come home.
It's not practice, it's training!
I'm off!
That's good...
It's not that Father dislikes
nii-san after all.
Nii-san graduated from the Academy
at the top of his class at age seven.
He learned to use
the Sharingan at age eight.
And he was promoted
to Chunin at age ten.
But I've got the same Uchiha blood
flowing inside me as he does.
I won't lose to him!
You're not gonna tell me this is
the best you can do, are you?
You boast about your Ninja Way
and this is all you've got?
Are you still thinking that
I'm a member of your comrade game?
If that's the case you're...
a hopeless fool!
Stop wasting time!
Give me all you've got
you number one hyperactive
knucklehead Ninja!
hitotsu hitotsu omoidaseba
when I recalled the parts one by one,
subete wakatteita kigashite ita no ni
I felt as though I had understood everything
iroaseta kotoba wa
faded words
boku no sugu soba ni oite atta
which I kept so close to me
kotae no denai yoru to
speechless nights,
a hint of warmth,
hitokira no nukumori to
and this distant yearning for you
haruka kanata no akogare to
I live,
tada sore dake wo
simply repeating this cycle
kurikaeshi boku wa ikite iru
held in my two hands
kono ryoute ni kakaete iru mono
a droplet of time
toki no shizuku
softly clutching forgotten memories
sotto nigirishimete wasureta kioku
lost words
nakushita kotoba
I'll keep these thoughts...
kono omoi wa
Just as Neji said,
it seems Sasuke's in
the darkness right now.
Damn it.
He really did hit me with all his might.
Hey Sasuke, am I not your comrade
or anything anymore?!
Don't all those things we
did together in Team 7
mean anything to you?!
Next episode
"Enlightenment, The Secret of the Mangekyou Sharingan."